8051 Meade St, Westminster, CO 80031

□ (+1) 303-903-5681 | **S** tylerjw@gmail.com | **O** tylerjw | **S** tylerweaver

Summary_

Highly motivated software engineer with experience leading long-term software projects involving optimizing algorithms for wireless communication. Embedded electronics hobbyist who enjoys using software and hardware to automate and solve problems. Interested in working on a team creating meaningful products.

Skills

Programming C/C++, Python, Matlab, JavaScript, Perl, Groovy, Processing, Java

Tools GCC, GDB, Make, Valgrind, SublimeText, Git, SVN, GPG, Bash

Embedded Arduino, RPi, Mbed, ARM, SPI, I2C, GPS, CV, IMU

Work Experience _____

LGS Innovations Westminster, CO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III Jun. 2014 - PRESENT

- Optimized C++ polyphase resampler and fir filter to run on ARM with NEON instructions
 - Filter design using same method as fir2 using fftw
 - Generic resampling implementation for arbitrary upsample and downsample rates
 - Used compiler optimizer output and knowledge of architecture to structure data and loop to take advantage of vectorization
 - Resulting fir filter and resampler used less instructions than intel IPP implementation and ran only 8x slower on A53 than on an i7 using intel optimized vector routines
 - Optimizing for vectorization resulted in 10x speed up over simple for loops
- Interface library for new SDR using protobuf messaging and VRT over ethernet
 - Protobuf messaging with thread for asynchronous status updating
 - VRT over UDP for receiving sample data over a 10Ge link
- Adversarial Research using physical layer implementation of 802.11b with SDR
 - Prototype C++ code using USRP to test RTS/CTS ranging technique
 - Developed unique method to improve ranging measurements based on observed behavior of AP messaging
 - Debugging using Wireshark to observe call and response
- · Created library for detecing oddly configured cellular basestations
- P25 scanner library
 - Prototyped in python, Implemented in C++
 - FFT narrow band energy window detect for fast scanning
 - FSW search used for timing and frequency offset correction
 - Viterbi, Reed-Solomon, BCH, and CRC Decoding
 - Framing and Message Parsing for all Broadcast messages
- Radio interface libraries for scanner application
 - Epig Sidekig with Placekig GPS
 - Ettus USRP N210 and B210 with support for hotplugging
- MPT1327 scanner library
 - Prototyped in matlab, Implemented in C++
 - Goertzel based fast reject for fast scanning
 - IPP Parallelized FM demodulator
 - Feedback timing recovery algorithm for MSK
 - CRC checker and Bit/Message parsing
- Ported matlab library for unknown signal analysis into C++
 - Arbitrary PSK and FSK input signal characterization
 - Implemented algorithms in C++ based off matlab code written by PhD

TecStar Consulting Broomfield, CO Mar. 2014 - Jun. 2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

· Selenium automation testing of websites with Python and Java

· Android app development for Rachio sprinkler controller

SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS SYSTEMS OPERATOR/MAINTAINER (25S)

Colorado Army National Guard

5/19th SFGA

Oct. 2008 - Oct. 2016

• Deployed in support of Special Operations Task Force East in Afghanistan (2013)

- · Developed software to automate extracting and converting geo locations from Google Earth files

Tyler J. Weaver · Résumé JANUARY 21, 2019

Education

DeVry University Westminster, CO

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY

- 3.96 GPA
- · Weather balloon payload navigation project
- Tutor for engineering program students

Extracurricular Activity

Enbedded Electronics Lakewood, CO

RALLY BUILD ENDURANCE RACE TEAM

Dec. 2018

Aug. 2010 - Mar. 2014

- Microcontroller CAN bus communication
- Power control circuits for motor control and high side switching
- Sensor signal conditioning circuits
- Current measuring using Opamp

Automation for Airbnb using Smartthings controller

Englewood, CO

FORK OF OPEN SOURCE DOOR LOCK SMART APP

Aug. 2017

- iCal parser and event logic for setting lock codes for each guest based on phone number
- Push notifications to phone app when guest uses their code for the first time

Co-driver computer for race car

Englewood, CO

Jul. 2017

WEAVERING RALLY TEAM

- Embedded system for assisting co-driver during competition
- GPS tracking and timing on Arduino microcontroller with 7-segment display
- · Competed in Rally Colorado 2017

Software for identifying ideal rental properties

Englewood, CO

AUTOMATED INVESTMENT ADVISOR

Mar. 2017 - Jun. 2017

- Scrapy scrapers for Realtor to find new listings
- Automated AWS EC2 Proxy instances for defeating Realtor.com tracking of bots
- MongoDb database for storing listings for analysis
- Airbnb scraper for finding similar properties listed for short term rental
- Daily PDF report generated using latex
- Developed locally and then deployed onto AWS
- Attempted to sell reports to Realtors

Colorado Robot Challenge Golden, CO

COMPUTER VISION ON EMBEDDED HARDWARE

Oct. 2013 - Mar. 2014

- Real-time firmware for 3d stereo vision sensor on XMOS and Nvidia hardware
- Custom BCB prototyping with surface mount components

splintermail.com Westminster, CO

INSTALL SCRIPTS AND TESTING

Oct. 2017

- · MacOS install script
- · Beta testing

January 21, 2019 Tyler J. Weaver · Résumé